<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<document>
	<title><![CDATA[Songbook-Client 0.7]]></title>
	<allow_com>1</allow_com>
	<template><![CDATA[article.php]]></template>
	<chapo><![CDATA[]]></chapo>
	<content><![CDATA[<p>I'm really glad to announce the version 0.7 of the <a href="http://github.com/crep4ever/songbook-client/">Songbook-Client</a>! A lot of new features have found their way in this version :)</p>

<p>Most of the changes are related to the song editor. Here are some highlights for the most visible updates.</p>

<h3>Graphical editor for metadata</h3>

<p>No doubt, this is the biggest change and you can't possibly miss it! The metadata of songs are seamlessly handled by the editor ie title, artist name, album, cover, diagrams etc.
Here is a screenshot:</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-new-song.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-new-song.png" height="300" alt="new-song" /></a>
<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-song-editor.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-song-editor.png" height="300" alt="song-editor" /></a>

<ul>
<li>the cover can be dropped from an external image file</li>
<li>the icon with two arrows corresponds to the \transpose macro for chord transposition (see tooltips for more info)</li>
<li>LaTeX environnements (verse, chorus, bridge, scripture) have their own background color (that may be disabled in the preferences dialog)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Spell-checking</h3>

<p>The song editor now support spell-checking
via <a href="http://hunspell.sourceforge.net/">hunspell</a> library
(widely used in projects such as Firefox, Chrome or LibreOffice). The
appropriate dictionary is loaded based on the language of the
song. Unfortunately, inline chords tend to produce a lot of false
positives.</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-spellchecker.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-spellchecker.png" height="200" alt="spellchecker" /></a>


<h3>Query replace</h3>

<p>A new button in the toolbar provides find/replace all features. The
dialog ui is functional but will be improved following gedit's for the
next version.</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-find-replace.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-find-replace.png" height="200" alt="find-replace" /></a>


<h3>Completion menu for macros</h3>

<p>Just hit Ctrl+space to popup the menu and pickup the macro you want :) Huge user-friendly improvement !</p>


<h3>Diagram editor</h3>

<p>Diagrams can be edited via a dedicated dialog. Here is a screenshot:</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-diagram-editor.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-diagram-editor.png" height="200" alt="diagram-editor" /></a>


<h3>Cancel progress bars</h3>

<p>A new button has been added to progress bars to cancel the current process:</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-progress-bar.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-progress-bar.png" height="30" alt="progress-bar" /></a>


<h3>Library download</h3>

<p>A few tweaks for this dialog displaying download speed and received
bytes. Note that a mirror url allows one to download the library from
patacrep's archive
(<a href="../../data/documents/songbook.tar.gz">songbook.tar.gz</a>) (the git snapshot is still available)</p>

<a href="../../data/images/sbc07-download-bar.png"><img src="../../data/images/sbc07-download-bar.png" width="80%"  alt="download-bar" /></a>


<p>And of course, there is a lot of smaller changes and bug fixes.
Congrats to Lohrun for its design and code for the song editor (and
Debian packages too!) ! Kudos !</p>

<p>Downloads are
available <a href="http://www.patacrep.com/en/static1/downloads#Songbook-Client">here</a>
as usual. Finaly, the Songbook-Client now has its own PPA for Ubuntu:</p>

<div class="unix">
<code>$ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:romain-goffe/patacrep
$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install songbook-client</code>
</div>

<p>I really hope there won't be too many bugs (edit: well, it seems there was a huge amount of them :/)/</p>

<p>That's all folks!</p>]]></content>
	<tags><![CDATA[songbook-client]]></tags>
	<meta_description><![CDATA[]]></meta_description>
	<meta_keywords><![CDATA[]]></meta_keywords>
	<title_htmltag><![CDATA[]]></title_htmltag>
</document>
